Kenneth Wardlow

Full-stack web developer using my experience in team leadership with robotic technologies to build better experiences for the end-user. I was constantly challenged with ways to make are companies remotely operated vehicles perform the tasks the customer needed. I recently earned a certificate in full-stack development from The University of Texas Austin, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js, and responsive web design. I have a strong passion for problem-solving and turning new ideas into realities. Recently worked on a team project with three other developers to create a single page application using jQuery, Html, CSS, and multiple API's to help people during quarantine in their drink making endeavors alcoholic or non-alcoholic. I am looking forward to using what I have learned to dive into new engaging problems and ideas to build better experiences on the web and to always be enhancing or creating something new.

111, Acacia
Lake Jackson, Tx 77566

(979) 292-4562

Kenneth@wardlowservices.com

EXPERIENCE

Team Industrial, Alvin, Tx — NDT Technician Level 2

August 2019 - PRESENT

Perform Quality control inspections in various chemical plants and oil and gas industry. Throughout the country

Dow Chemical, Freeport, Tx — Sr. Maintenance Robotics technologist, M&E

September 2017 - May 2019

Help implement and create their still functioning robotic department. Operated remotely operated vehicles to perform remote inspection including Ariel and submersibles inspections. Trained Other employees throughout North America and Canada on the use and operation of this new technology and equipment. Along with problem solving to modify the robotic capabilities to perform tasks not originally intended by design with 3d printing and modification.

Southern Technical Services, Freeport, Tx — NDT Technician Level 2

October 2013 - September 2017

Performed Quality control inspections as in current job while creating their robotic department for Dow Chemical. And other companies they were contracted with.

EDUCATION

Austin Community College, Austin, Tx — Studied business and computer science

August 2009 - May 2011

Studied in business and computer science and business management. Was not able to complete the program due to unforeseen circumstances leading to having to move back to Lake Jackson

Brazosport Community College, Lake Jackson Tx — General studies

Aug 2004 - May 2007

Started college here initially to Transfer to Texas state in general studies and some computer courses Then transferred to Austin community college to attempt to finish out my studies before transferring to Texas state after

PROJECTS

BarMaid - Web App

After This application used multiple API's including the drink dB and tom-tom as well as google maps it provides the user with options to select specific drink of there choosing and provides the ingredients measurements and instructions to make the drink. If they can not decide it has a random option providing up to 10 randomly populated drinks with the same information to create them. Finally, they can use their geolocation to display the closest liquor stores in a 15-mile radius with links to google maps for directions and further relevant information. https://kennyward85.github.io/Project1-/

SKILLS

- Proficient in JavaScript Html CSS web design
- jQuery Dom manipulation.
- Node.js, express, handlebars, Mongo DB
- React.js, MySQL, Sequelize, database creation
- Some Python experience.

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kennethwardlow-950ba11a8/

https://github.com/Kennyward85

https://www.wardlowservices.com/

LANGUAGES

English